Inventory of the Conference on Cold War Broadcasting Impact proceedings
Hoover Institution Archives
Conference on Cold War Broadcasting Impact proceedings
2004-2005
2005C18
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Sound recordings and video tape of proceedings, transcripts of conference papers, photographs of conference participants, and printed matter relating to Radio Liberty and Radio Free Europe broadcasting to the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe. Conference sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace and the Cold War International History Project of the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars. Use copies of sound and video recordings available.
Conference on Cold War Broadcasting Impact (2004: Hoover Institution)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.
Cold War International History Project.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of all sound and video recordings in this collection are available for immediate access.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings and video tape of proceedings, transcripts of conference papers, photographs of conference participants, and printed matter relating to Radio Liberty and Radio Free Europe broadcasting to the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe. Conference sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace and the Cold War International History Project of the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars. Use copies of sound and video recordings available.
Radio Free Europe.; Radio Liberty.; Radio broadcasting--Soviet Union.; Radio broadcasting--Europe, Eastern.; Audiotapes.; Video tapes.
- 3.5" floppy disk (Bonner speech), 2004 October (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains a word processing file, Elena Bonner.doc, authored by Natasha Porfirenko. The file contains a Russian transliteration of the speech Bonner gave at the conference. For printout of speech text, see Box 2, Folder 6.
- 3.5" floppy disk (Henze memo), 2004 October (Box 1)
  Contains a word processing file, CONF.doc, authored by Paul B. Henze. The file contains a memo from Henze to Elena Danielson, "Radio Impact Conference; Topics not Covered." For printout of memo, see Box 2, Folder 10.
- Videorecording of Václav Havel video address to the conference, 2004 October 14; 1.0 VHS videocassette (Box 1)
  Access
  Use copy reference number: 2005c18_v_0002952
  A leading dissident during the Communist era, Václav Havel's writings reached his fellow citizens through the broadcasts of the RFE Czechoslovak Service. Invited to address the Conference on Cold War Broadcasting Impact at the Hoover Institution in 2004, Havel was unable to attend but recorded for conference participants his thoughts on the significance of RFE.
- Sound recordings of proceedings, 2004 October 14-15; 14.0 CDs (Box 1)
  Use copy reference number: 2005c18_a_0005877
- Fifteen sound cassettes, 2004 October 14-15 (Box 1)
- Digital image files, 2004 October 13-16; 7.0 CDs (Box 1)
  CDs (two of which are duplicates of others) contain .jpg image files of the conference and participants. For print versions of a subset of these photos, see Photographs (Box 2, Folder 14).
- Conference program, 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 1)
- "Papers for Presentation on Thursday, October 14, 2004,", 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
  Includes draft conference papers by Gregory Mitrovich, Paul B. Henze, Alan L. Heil Jr., George Woodard, R. Eugene Parta, E. I. Bashkirova, Lechoslaw Galikowski, Pawel Machcewicz, Jane Curry, and Oldřich Tůma.
- "A Preliminary Empirical Assessment of the Roles of Radio Liberty and Western Broadcasting to the USSR During the Cold War: A Study Based on Audience Research Findings, 1970-1991," R. Eugene Parta, 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 4)
- "Listening Rates to Western Radio Stations in Poland, Hungary, Czechoslovakia, Romania and Bulgaria, 1962-1988: Longitudinal Listening Trend Charts," compiled by R. Eugene Parta, 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Elena Bonner speech (Russian transliteration), circa 2004 October 14 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  Printout from a word processing file on a floppy disk. Due to the document being created in an earlier version of Word, there are some extraneous symbols present.
- "Papers for Presentation on Friday, October 15, 2004,", 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 7-8)
  Includes draft conference papers by Nestor Ratesh, Germina Nagat, Jordan Baev, István Rév, János Berecz, Amier Weiner, Peter Zvagulis, and Wladimir Tolz.
- "Radio Free Europe/Radio Free Liberty Documents, 1953-1986," document reader, 2004 October (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Memorandum from Paul B. Henze to Elena Danielson, "Radio Impact Conference; Topics not Covered,", 2004 October 27 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Cold War Broadcasting Impact: Conference Summary, 2005 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  Includes the following sections: I. Preface, II. Cold War Broadcasting Impact: Conference Summary, III. Cold War International Broadcasting: Lessons Learned, IV. Conference Participants.
- Voices of Hope: The Story of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty exhibit postcards, 2004 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- "Cardinal Miloslav Vlk, Archbishop of Prague on the Role of Radio Free Europe," translated by Olga Kopecka, condensed and edited by Ross Johnson, photocopy, undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
  Excerpts of speech delivered at a Czech Christian Academy symposium in Prague, October 13, 2003.
- Photographs, 2004 October 13-16 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  100 color prints (includes some duplicates) of conference participants. Includes photos of Suzanne Ament, Elena Bashkirova, Elena Bonner, James Brown, Robert Conquest, Richard Cummings, Jane Curry, Elena Danielson, Thomas Dine, John Dunlop, Charles Gati, Leszek Gawlikowski, Alan Heil, Paul Henze, David Holloway, A. Ross Johnson, Kenneth Jowitt, Gail Lapidus, Pawel Machcewicz, Gregory Mitrovich, Norman Naimark, Christian Ostermann, Eugene Parta, Mark Pomar, István Rev, Svetlana Savranskaya, Anatol Shmelev, George Shultz, Eugeniusz Smolar, Gene Sosin, Oldrich Tuma, Amir Weiner, Sharon Wolchik, George Woodard, and others.